This will be the equivalent of the long procedure we had before
这和我们之前的较长的过程是等同的
We are checking if the name at position "zero" is equal to D
我们要检查在位置零的结果是否等于 D
or the result of name at position zero is equal to N
或者是否等于 N
That produces the same result
这样产生的结果是相同的
and we've introduced the new construct "or"
我们已经介绍了新运算符 or
which gives us the logic "or" of the two operands on its left and right
其左右两边的运算对象的逻辑关系是 or
so just to see how "or" works
下面我们看看 or 运算具体是怎样的
we can use "or" like this
我们可以这样使用 or
So if we have "True" or "False", the value of "True" or "False" is "True"
True or False 的值为 True
"True" or "True" is also "True", but "False" or "False" is "False"
True or True 的值也是 True 但 False or False 的值则为 False
And I'm showing these boolean literals
我这里用的是布尔型常量
This could be any expression we want, like we use the name at position zero here
实际上可以用任何表达式 比如我们在位置零所用的名字
The one important thing that "or" does is different from other operators
重要的是 or 和其它运算符不同
It only evaluates what it needs to
它只计算它需要计算的
So here's an important example
下面是一个重要的例子
So we could say "True" or "this_is_an_error"
True or this_is_an_error (这是一个错误)
That will also evaluate to "True"
结果将为 True
even though if I just look at "this_is_an_error" by itself
尽管如果我们只看 this_is_an_error 本身
that's an undefinable variable
这是一个没有定义的变量
We didn't define the variable "this_is_an_error"
我们没有定义 this_is_an_error 这个变量
because we already found that the first part was "True", we don't get an error
因为我们已经知道第一部分为 True 我们就不会得到错误
If we try to evaluate instead of "True" or "this_is_an_error"
如果我们运算的不是 True or this_is_an_error
if we evaluate "False" or "this_is_an_error"
而是 False or this_is_an_error
it's necessary to look at the second operand and then we will get an error
那就有必要看第二部分了 于是我们会得到一个错误
So let's try that, we are doing "False" or" this_is_an_error"
下面我们来试一下 False or this_is_an_error
to know whether the "or" is "True" or "False", we need to look at the second operand
要知道这个 or 是 True 还是 False 我们需要看第二部分
and that's not defined
第二部分是没有定义的
This behavior of "or" will turn out to be very useful
or 的这种行为会非常有用
We'll see other places where we rely on the second operand not getting evaluated
我们还会碰到其它不处理第二个运算对象的情况
if the first one is "True"
如果第一个运算对象为 True
So to summarize, here's what the "or" construct looks like
下面我们总结一下 or 运算是怎样进行的
So if the first expression evaluates to "True"
如果第一个表达式的值为 True
then the value of the "or" construct is "True"
那么该 or 结构的值为 True
and in fact the Python interpreter does not evaluate it
事实上 Python 解释器也不会处理第二部分
If the value of the first expression is "False"
如果第一个表达式的值为 False
then the value of the "or" construct is the value of the second expression
那么该 or 结构的值就是第二个表达式的值